heritage.org 2002-06-05

# The Heritage Foundation -- Privacy Policy

| 

**Heritage**  
Who We Are  
**Publications**  
[Library  
](http://www.heritage.org/library/)News & Views   
**Features  
**Mandate 2001  
Policy Calculators **  
**E-mail Lists  
[Internships](http://www.heritage.org/internships/) _[  
](http://www.policyreview.com/)_**Events**  
[Calendar  
](http://www.heritage.org/events/) Heritage Live!  
**Resources  
** [Policy Experts  
](http://www.policyexperts.org/)Speakers  

**Key Issues  
**ABM / Missile Def.  
Africa  
Asia / Pacific  
Budget  
Crime  
Education  
Energy and Env't  
Europe  
Family  
Gov't Reform  
Health Care  
Int'l Organizations  
Internet and Tech.  
Labor  
Latin America  
Legal Issues  
Middle East  
National Security  
Political Philosophy  
Regulation  
Russia and Eurasia  
Smart Growth  
Social Security  
Taxes  
Trade/Foreign Aid  
Urban  
Welfare

Send this page to  
a friend today!  

**   
FREE Spring 2001  
Publications Catalog**

| 

|  **Privacy Policy**

> **The Heritage Foundation's Privacy Policy**  
>  Your privacy on the Internet is important to us. As part of the operation and customization feature of The Heritage Foundation's web site ("heritage.org"), we gather certain types of information from users, and we would like to explain the types of information we gather, what we do with them, and how to correct or change the information.
> 
>   
>  **Information Collected By heritage.org**  
>  heritage.org collects two types of information from users: personal data such as zip code, email address and demographic information; and aggregated data such as information about traffic patterns on heritage.org (for example, how many users log on to heritage.org on a daily basis). 
> 
> **Aggregated Information**  
>  Aggregated information, such as which pages users visit, is collected through various means. One of these ways is through an IP address, a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web. Web servers, the computers that "serve up" Web pages, automatically identify your computer by its IP address. When you request a page from heritage.org, our servers log your IP address. heritage.org does not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, so although your session will be logged, your session will remain anonymous to us. heritage.org collects IP addresses for the purposes of system administration only. 
> 
> **Use of Cookies**  
>  heritage.org uses cookies to automate the process of logging on to certain areas of the site. The heritage.org cookie is a small data file stored on your computer that contains a single, randomly assigned user ID number. By recognizing this ID number, heritage.org can automatically provide you with the personalized content for which you requested. Cookies can neither read any other files on your computer, nor damage your computer. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you'd prefer, you can set your browser to refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent. 
> 
> **Use of Information Collected by heritage.org**  
>  heritage.org uses both the personal and aggregated information we collect for multiple purposes. The information is used to improve the content of the site, to customize the content and/or layout of the site for each individual user, and if requested, to provide information services by email to the user. After registration, users will receive a single email message confirming registration. The Heritage Foundation will never disclose your personally identifiable information to a third party unless required to do so by court order, law or governmental agency. 
> 
> **Information Security at heritage.org**  
>  Heritage Foundation employees understand the need for user privacy and heritage.org has appointed a privacy policy administrator to monitor privacy practices. Access to user data is strictly limited and can only be accessed by specific individuals who have the necessary username and password combination. A log is maintained to record who has accessed the data. This log is checked at least weekly for possible security breaches. 
> 
> **Children and Privacy**  
>  The Heritage Foundation encourages parents and guardians to spend time with their children online and to be fully familiar with the sites visited by their children. In general, heritage.org will not contain content that is reasonably considered unsuitable for children. 
> 
> **Links to Other Sites**  
>  It is important to note that heritage.org contains links to sites other than heritage.org, and that those sites may not follow the same privacy policies as heritage.org. For instance, a link in the "Helpful Links" section of heritage.org will take you away from heritage.org to an entirely different site. 
> 
> **Changes to the Privacy Policy**  
>  The Heritage Foundation reserves the right to change the policy on use of information collected. Any changes in policy will be noted in a revised privacy policy statement and will be posted at least 30 days prior to implementation. You may direct any privacy policy questions to [info@heritage.org](mailto:info@heritage.org).   
  
---|---|---
